Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Bettison, Oscar, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Embedded Bandcamp audio files and Google Docs documents were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, press relating to him and his works, a calendar of his events, a gallery of images of Bettison, and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer of music that makes use of traditional and electric instruments for chamber and concert pieces. He also creates percussion instruments for his works. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Bielawa, Lisa, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  New crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.lisabielawa.net/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded images, video, and Soundcloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains descriptions of Bielawa's compositions, which include concert and orchestral pieces as well as operas. It also has a biography of the artist, who is a vocalist as well as a composer, information about the projects she is working on, a calendar of her events, examples of her work in the form of embedded audio and video files, and images of Bielawa. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Biggs, Hayes, February 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://hayesbiggs.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a calendar of his events, and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a choral singer, conductor, and composer of classically-influenced pieces for instrumental and vocal performance by orchestras, chamber music ensembles, choruses, and soloists. Capture of the site began in February 2015. This description is based on the January 2018 capture of the site.
- Bischoff, John, July 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.johnbischoff.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Parts of the live site involving Soundcloud and Vimeo were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Bischoff is a performer and composer specializing in live computer music. The website details his works and contains a biography of the artist, a calendar of his events, links to examples of his compositions in the form of SoundCloud and Vimeo files, a discography of his published albums, information about his individual works, a bibliography of his prose writings, and two galleries of embedded image files depicting the artist and his performances. Capture of the site began in July 2017. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
- Bleckmann, Theo, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://theobleckmann.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Features of the site involving Flash do not function in the archived copy due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of Bleckmann, a jazz composer and vocalist, examples of his works in the form of embedded audio, image, and video files, images of Bleckmann, and information about the projects he is working on. Capture of the site began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Borbetomagus, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5860; 7 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.borbetomagus.com/, http://www.kunstmuseumsg.ch/voicecrack/,http://andy.guhl.net/, http://homepage.swissonline.ch/bots/, http://www.shakingray.com/introduction.shtml, http://www.furious.com/perfect/borbetomagus.html and http://www.paristransatlantic.com/magazine/interviews/borbetomagus.html in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Some external sites were included due to their contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl. These sites are http://www.kunstmuseumsg.ch/voicecrack/, http://andy.guhl.net/, http://homepage.swissonline.ch/bots/, http://www.shakingray.com/introduction.shtml, http://www.furious.com/perfect/borbetomagus.html and http://www.paristransatlantic.com/magazine/interviews/borbetomagus.html.
  An internal page was not captured due to technological constraints. This page is located at http://borbetomagus.com/concerts.htm
  The website contains a discography of the artist and a calendar of his events. Borbetomagus is a musical group composed of Jim Sauter on saxophones, Don Dietrich on saxophones, Donald Miller on guitar, and Adam Nodelman on bass. The group was formed in 1979 and specializes in free improvisation/noise music. Capture of the website began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Botelho, Paul J., May 2014- ongoing; cuid5861; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://pauljbotelho.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his works, including musical compositions, visual art, and software that he has designed, and a calendar of his events. Botelho's music includes several short operas as well as acoustic and electro-acoustic works. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Botti, Susan, February 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.susanbotti.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her compositions and projects, news relating to Botti, a discography of her published albums, a calendar of her events, and examples of her work in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight her work as a soprano singer and composer of music featuring classical and improvisational styles, for both vocal and instrumental performance. Capture of the site began in February 2015. This description is based on the January 2018 capture of the site.
- Boyce, Douglas, February 2015- ongoing; cuid5855; 2 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of www.douglasboyce.net/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his works, and reviews of Boyce and his music. Boyce specializes in chamber music that draws on Renaissance and modern themes. Capture of the site began in February 2015. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Branca, Glenn, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5882; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.glennbranca.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, reviews of the artist and his works, a list of his most important compositions, and a calendar of Branca's events. JWPlayer video files were not captured due to technological constraints. Branca's compositions span a variety of genres, such as rock, large and small ensemble works for acoustic and electric instruments, opera, ballet, choral pieces, and music meant to accompany film, dance, theater, and art installations. Capture of website began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Brazelton, Kitty, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5936; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of kitbraz.com, listenforwhat.wordpress.com, and kitbraz.info in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, images associated with her music or of Brazelton herself, and a discography of her published works. Brazelton is a composer and singer of classical and rock music. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
- Bresnick, Martin, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5848; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.martinbresnick.com/#/homepage in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, 8 embedded audio files recording a selection of his musical works, information about his projects and works, a calendar of his events, and images files of the artist. Bresnick's works span the genres of opera, chamber music, symphonic music, film scores, and computer music. Capture of website began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Britt, N. Cameron, April 2014-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of ncameronbritt.com and cameronbritt.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  N. Cameron Britt (b. 1974) is a composer, percussionist, and instrument builder. The website contains a biography of the artist, blog posts on instrument building and music, and discography. In 2020, the URL changed and reformatted and mostly consists of video and Soundcloud players of his music.
- Brouwer, Margaret, February 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.margaretbrouwer.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of composer and violinist Margaret Brouwer, a calendar of her events, examples of her works in the form of audio and video files, and information about the projects she is involved in, which include several instrumental ensembles performing classically influenced music. Capture of the site began in February 2015. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
- Browning, Zack, February 2015-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Site crawls are accrued annually.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://zackbrowning.github.io in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Zack Browning is composer, conductor, and performer, playing trumpet with the Atlanta Symphony Orchestra and served as co-director of the Atlanta New Music Ensemble. The website contains news, listing of his compositions and recordings, reviews of his work, and information on the Salvatore Martirano Memorial Composition Award. This description is based on the March 2020 crawl.
- Bryars, Gavin, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5879; 2 websites in 2 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.gavinbryars.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Portions of the website had to be crawled separately to ensure adequate capture.
  The site contains a biography of the artist, reviews of his work, a calendar of his events, image files of the artist and his performances, 6 embedded video files recording Bryars' performances, his discography and list of works, and details about his collaborations, projects, and works in other performance media. His musical works encompass the genres of theater, dance, chamber music, and opera. He is also an accomplished bassist. Capture of site began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Burt, Warren, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.warrenburt.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded PDF files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a discography of his published albums, press relating to Burt and his works, downloadable versions of his scores and essays, interviews with Burt, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as an instrument maker and composer of microtonal music using acoustic, electronic, and computer instruments. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the January 2018 capture of the site.
- Byron, Don, May 2017; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  The website contains a brief biography of the artist and several of his projects, a list of his performances, a discography, information about his compositions, and excerpts of articles written about him. The music featured on Byron's website, which he describes as "a sound above genre", utilizes a variety of instruments and styles, including jazz and classical. Capture of the website began in May 2017. The site was taken down shortly after the first capture. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://donbyron.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Calianno, Vincent, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5852; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://droplid.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, his prose works, and information about his music. Calianno's works include such genres as opera, musicals, large and small ensemble pieces, electro-acoustic music, and music for films. Capture of website began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Carrick, Richard, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.richardcarrick.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Soundcloud audio files and Youtube and Vimeo video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, excerpts of articles and news written about Carrick and his music, a calendar of his events, a discography of his published albums, and examples of his works in the form of embedded video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer and conductor, as well as pianist. His compositions are largely classically-influenced instrumental, with some multimedia pieces, and intended for large ensemble, chamber, and solo performance. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Casenave, Gustavo, April 2014-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://www.casenave.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  This is the website for Gustavo Casenave, a Uruguayan pianist and composer. The website contains information on his musical projects, the Casenave Music Institute, the Fula Records music label, his discography, videos of performances, and an image gallery. This description is based on the March 2020 crawl.
- Cerrone, Christopher, February 2014-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of christophercerrone.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Website was rescoped to attempt to capture the Issuu publications, Soundcloud audio and Vimeo videos embedded in the website.
  This is the professional website for composer Christopher Cerrone, featuring a biography, a catalogue of compositions for opera, choral, solo instrumentalist, chamber ensemble, percussion, and electronic instruments, a news feed for accolades, performances, upcoming releases, and personal news, a list of ensembles playing Cerrone's work in the current season, a discography, a selection of performance videos, and a list of press coverage of Cerrone's work. The site was first captured in February of 2014. The site was updated circa 2017 to replace the 'Media' page with photos, videos, and embedded audio with a 'Watch' page featuring only performance video. This update also saw the addition of a 'Press' page. The site has not been changed significantly since that update except to reflect new work and press coverage. This description is based on the November 2019 crawl of the site.
- Chadabe, Joel, August 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.joelchadabe.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his compositions, and examples of his prose writing. The music featured on the site makes use of electronic instruments and interactive composition, as well as orchestral ensembles. Capture of the site began in August 2015. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
- Chase, Ryan, May 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.ryanmchase.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Soundcloud audio on the site was captured, but does not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the composer and pianist Ryan Chase, examples of his works in the form of embedded audio files, and a catalog of his compositions. The music featured on the site was composed for orchestral and chamber ensembles with jazz and classical influences. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Chatham, Rhys, July 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  New site craws are accrued annually.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.rhyschatham.net/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded images on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the guitarist, trumpet player, and composer Rhys Chatham, a calendar of his events, and information about his works and projects. The music featured on the site makes use of electric and acoustic instruments for ensemble performance. The website also highlights his work in the Rhys Chatham Ensemble. Capture of the site began in July 2017. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
  Rhys Chatham Ensemble
- Cheung, Anthony, May 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.acheungmusic.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, excerpts of articles and news written about Cheung and his music, a discography of his published albums, and examples of his works in the form of embedded prose writings and audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer of classically-influenced instrumental works for soloists and ensembles of various sizes, and as a pianist. Many of his pieces feature computer-generated music as well. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Childs, Mary Ellen, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5904; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.maryellenchilds.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, 1 embedded video file of an interview with Childs, reviews of her works, a calendar of her events, a discography and list of works, 12 embedded audio files of her compositions, and information about her past and current projects. Some images from the site were not captured due to technological constraints. Childs is a prolific composer known for her novel use of percussion and accordions in her music, which includes strong visual elements such as theater and dance. Capture of website began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Church, Joseph, February 2015- ongoing; cuid5902; 4 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of www.churchmuse.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a gallery of images relating to Church's music, including pictures of Church himself, and examples of his musical works in the form of embedded audio files. Church has been actively involved in musical theater in addition to his compositional work of opera and chorus music. He is an accomplished pianist. Capture of the site began in February 2015. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Clyne, Anna, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5905; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.annaclyne.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.